Alaina Kafkes

Awards

Anita Borg Institute GHC Scholar

June 2016. Won an all-expenses paid trip to the Grace Hopper Celebration for excellence in innovation & leadership.

PanHellenic Scholar

May 2016. Received a merit scholarship that honors exceptional undergraduates of Greek-American heritage.

Personal Projects

Dibz

January 2016 – June 2016.

Founded and developed a web app that offers online sellers the ability to generate a bitlink to share a listing in informal, online communities. Launched to 50+ beta testers in June 2016. Technologies used: Javascript, RiotJS, Firebase API, HTML/CSS.

Rude

February 2016 (HackIllinois).

Coded Android app that encourages users to spend quality time socializing without checking their phone. Technologies used: Java, Facebook API.

June 2016 - Present.

Developing Rude as an iPhone app. Languages used: Swift.

Myrror

January 2016 - March 2016.

Developed a web app cast onto a two-way mirror that assesses the user's body confidence using the principles of social comparison theory and waist size approximations. Pitched proof of concept to 50+ students and professors, which was selected to be pursued by faculty of the Feinberg School of Medicine. Technologies used: Javascript, JQuery, Firebase API.

Education

Northwestern University | Computer Science, minor in Chemistry Anticipated June 2017. Cumulative GPA: 3.69/4.00

Work Experience

GE Healthcare | Software Engineering Intern

June 2016 – Present. Developing the Media Manager web application, which expedites the binding of images & videos to patient data in the Centricity Clinical Archive. Spearheaded the creation of a mock server to prevent unit testing with sensitive patient information. Technologies used: AngularJS 2, NodeJS, TypeScript, C#, HTML/CSS.

Northwestern University | Teaching Assistant

December 2015 – Present. Assists students in introductory programming course through the creation of a network and with object-oriented programming questions. Languages used: C++.

National Science Foundation | REU Intern

June 2015 – August 2015. Coded scripts that computationally optimized aluminum-biomolecule conjugates in order to find a cheap alternative to gold and silver in biodiagnostics. One of twenty young engineers selected for a prestigious National Science Foundation fellowship. Languages used: Python.

Extracurriculars & Offices Held

Women in Computing | Internal President

April 2015 – Present. Established and chairs first-ever mentorship program for undergraduate & graduate women in tech, with 40+ participants in the pilot program. Organizes and teaches at weekly, campus-wide hack nights for 100+ attendees.

EPIC | Project Lead & Web Developer

April 2016 – Present. Built website for the Northwestern Venture Challenge. Technologies used: Sass, Gulp, Javascript, HTML/CSS.

Peer Health Exchange | Senior Health Educator

September 2014 – Present. Teaches the ninth grade health & sexual education curriculum at Chicago Public Schools.

Kappa Delta Sorority | Academic Excellence Chair

November 2015 – Present. Hosted Kappa Delta's first-ever resume building workshop and launched chapter-wide resume database.